WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- BUT IF WE...
BUT HOW CAN...
- JESUS CHRIST.
- SO THIS MEANS THAT,
UH...
- SO NO ONE KILLED
ANY HOMELESS MEN.
- NO SERIAL KILLER.
SOME WERE RANDOM KILLINGS,
SOME WERE NATURAL DEATHS
THAT WERE LIKELY MANIPULATED.
BUT THEY'RE NOT LINKED
IN ANY WAY.
- BUT WHY?
- THE DETECTIVES USED
THE MONEY TO FUND A CASE
AGAINST THE DRUG
TRAFFICKERS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE SLAYINGS IN
THE VACANTS A YEAR AGO.
- LAST WEEK'S ARRESTS AND
SEIZURES WERE A DIRECT RESULT.
- SO LET ME JUST
UNDERSTAND THIS...
SO I'VE BEEN GOING OUT THERE
FOR WEEKS,
SLAMMING THE GOVERNOR FOR
HIS NEGLECT OF THE
HOMELESS AND DECLARING
HOW WE WILL STOP
AT NOTHING TO FINDHE
PERSON RESPONSIBLE FOR
PREYING ON THE HOMELESS
AND ALL THE WHILE--
HEY, NORMAN,
THIS IS MY ASS HERE.
- THAT'S TRUE, BOSS.
BUT IT DOES HAVE A
CERTAIN CHARM TO IT.
THEY MANUFACTURED
AN ISSUE TO GET PAID,
WE MANUFACTURED AN
ISSUE TO GET YOU
ELECTED GOVERNOR.
EVERYBODY'S GETTIN'
WHAT THEY NEED BEHIND
SOME MAKE-BELIEVE.
- THE DETECTIVES INVOLVED
WILL BE SUSPENDED AND
ULTIMATELY FIRED,
AT THE LEAST.
BEYOND THAT,
A CRIMINAL PROSECUTION
ON FRAUD AND PERJURY
CHARGES IS PROBABLE.
- SO, WHAT, YOU'RE SAYING
WE CALL A PRESS CONFERENCE
AND WE SAY,
"HEY, BY THE WAY,
"ALL THAT STUFF ABOUT HOMELESS
PEOPLE GETTING KILLED AND
"THE GOVERNOR CUTTING
THE SAFETY NET AND US DOING
"EVERYTHING IN OUR POWER
TO CATCH THE GUY,
HEY, GUESS WHAT,
THE JOKE'S ON US?"
- NOT TO MENTION THAT
THE EVIDENCE AGAINST
THE TRAFFICKERS ARRESTED
LAST WEEK IS TAINTED.
THAT CASE COULD
COLLAPSE AS WELL.
- I DON'T FUCKING
BELIEVE THIS.
YOU TWO ARE ON POINT HERE.
WORD OF THIS GETS
DOWN TO ANNAPOLIS,
THE GOVERNOR'S
GONNA WRECK ME WITH IT.
AND IF IT COMES TO THAT,
YOU GUYS DROP ON YOUR SWORDS,
SO HELP ME.
- HOW DOES WORD
NOT GET OUT
ONCE WE SUSPEND
THE DETECTIVES?
NEVER MIND SENDING IT
TO THE GRAND JURY
- THE COPS THAT DID THIS,
THEY GOTTA GO.
YOU CANNOT BE TELLING ME
I HAVE TO LIVE WITH THIS.
- DEPUTY, COUNSELOR...
IF YOU TWO WILL EXCUSE US,
WE ARE GOING TO
DISCUSS THIS FIRST AS
A MATTER OF PUBLIC POLICY.
UNTIL WE CAN REASON THE
BEST WAY TO ADDRESS THIS,
DO NOTHING AND SPEAK
TO NO ONE
ABOUT ANY OF THIS.
- IF THIS BECOMES
PUBLIC IN THE WRONG WAY,
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
WERE LEGALLY RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE SITUATION,
GOOD PEOPLE
WHO WERE NONETHELESS IN A
SUPERVISORY ROLE HERE...
ARE GOING TO SUFFER.
AND THAT'S NOT THE
OUTCOME THAT ANYONE WANTS.
- WHAT MIKE IS SAYING IS
THAT WE NEED TO
BE VERY CAREFUL
ABOUT HOW TO PROCEED.
- I WISH I WAS STILL
AT THE NEWSPAPER
SO I COULD WRITE
ON THIS MESS.
IT'S TOO FUCKIN' GOOD.
www.wikisubtitles.net
www.thewire-france.com
THE WIRE - 5x10, #60,  series finale
" -30- "
www.ncicap.org
www.hbo.com/thewire
" ... the life of kings."
- H. L. Mencklen.
- LESTER. WHAT BRINGS YOU DOWN?
WE DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
SCHEDULED FROM YOU TODAY,
I DON'T THINK...
- 40,000 FROM THE SHOWBOAT
ON THE BOARDWALK.
26 AT THE BORGATA.
80 OVER THE LAST
YEAR AT THE TAJ MAHAL...
AND THAT'S JUST THE
ATLANTIC CITY CASINOS.
- I LIKE TO PLAY. SO WHAT?
- YOU LOST THREE TIMES
YOUR SALARY OVER
THE LAST TWO YEARS.
I RAN YOU THROUGH SENTINEL
TITLE AND CAME BACK
WITH SEVEN PAGES OF LIENS
AND A THIRD MORTGAGE
YOU FOLDED ON TWO MONTHS AGO.
GARY, YOU'RE DONE.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- WE FOUND SEALED GRAND
JURY PAPERS IN THE HOUSES
OF DRUG DEALERS.
AND WE'VE GOT PEOPLE
NAMING YOU ON IT.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM, GARY.
BUT YOU HAVE FRIENDS
IN THIS COURTHOUSE,
LIFELONG FRIENDS.
COP TO THE PROBLEM,
GIVE UP THE NAMES OF THOSE
THAT BOUGHT FROM YOU.
DISBARRED? YEAH, NO DOUBT.
BUT YOU PLAY IT CLEAN
FROM THIS MOMENT ON,
AND WE BOTH KNOW
YOU'LL PROBABLY WALK.
- WHY DID YOU LOOK AT ME?
- I RAN THE FINANCES
ON EVERYONE WHO WORKED
THIS UNIT OVER THE
LAST COUPLE YEARS.
YOU WERE THE ONLY BOGIE.
IF THE S.A.O. WEREN'T
SO SCREWED UP,
THEY'D HAVE BEEN
RUNNING BACKGROUND
CHECKS AS A ROUTINE.
BUT I GUESS YOU KNEW THAT.
- I ALWAYS WONDERED IF THEY'D
GET THEIR SHIT TOGETHER.
BUT THAT'S BALTIMORE,
ISN'T IT?
SO WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
- WELL, FOR STARTERS...
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
A PHONE CALL.
- McNULTY, FREAMON,
SYDNOR,
ANYONE WHO HAS THE SMELL OF
THIS ON THEM SHOULD BE GONE.
BEFORE THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS,
THEY SHOULD BE SUSPENDED
AND BEFORE THE END
OF THE WEEK, INDICTED.
- I KNOW, BUT...
- BUT WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS SHIT
STAND BECAUSE IT'LL
HURT CARCETTI TO AIR IT OUT?
INSTEAD OF CLEANING
HOUSE LIKE WE NEED TO,
HE'S UP THERE FIGURING
OUT HOW TO HIDE THE DIRT.
I SWEAR, I GOTTA MIND
TO CALL THE GOVERNOR MYSELF
AND JUST LET IT FLY.
- CEDRIC, YOU CAN'T.
- WHY NOT?
IF I LET THIS THING STAND,
I MIGHT AS WELL JUST
ROLL OVER AND PLAY DEAD
FOR EVERY POLICE
WHO KNOWS ABOUT THIS.
WE COVER THIS UP...
- CEDRIC, YOU CAN'T
DO ANYTHING.
THOSE ARE YOUR DETECTIVES.
THEY NEED SOMEONE TO BLAME,
THEY WILL MEASURE YOU FOR IT...
- I DON'T GIVE A FUCK.
- AND THEY'LL FIRE ME.
YOU HEARD STEINTORF...
I WAS IN CHARGE OF THIS THING.
I WAS ON THAT WIRETAP...
THIS IS MY CAREER.
THIS IS EVERYTHING.
YOU GO PUBLIC,
AND IT HURTS CARCETTI.
MAYBE HE DOESN'T GET
TO BE GOVERNOR.
BUT HE IS STILL THE MAYOR
AND BOND IS STILL MY BOSS
AND YOU KNOW THE WEIGHT
WILL NOT FALL ON THEM.
IT NEVER DOES.
- CHRIST.
- EVERYTHING
I'VE WORKED FOR, ALL THOSE YEARS
IN THAT COURTHOUSE...
PLEASE.
- 25 CENTS.
"BALTIMORE SUN."
SIR, "BALTIMORE SUN."
ONE QUARTER.
- KEEP IT.
- THANK YOU, SIR. THANK YOU.
- PEOPLE TIP PRETTY GOOD,
DON'T THEY?
- PAINING FOR WHAT
HE HAD DONE TO US.
I'M SORRY FOR HIM, MAN,
REALLY, BUT I STILL
CAN'T LET HIM COME UP
FROM THE BASEMENT.
YOU GONNA PUT ALL
THAT IN THE PAPER?
- THAT'S THE PLAN.
- EVEN THE PARTS
ABOUT SHERROD?
- YEAH.
- WHAT GOOD IS...
WHAT GOOD IS A STORY
LIKE THAT?
- LIKE WHAT?
- ME, SHERROD.
GETTIN' HIGH. NOT GETTIN' HIGH.
MY SISTER,
ALL THAT SHIT IN THERE.
WHAT GOOD DO ANY OF THAT
DO TO PUT IT IN THE NEWSPAPER?
- PEOPLE READ IT,
THEY THINK ABOUT IT.
MAYBE SEE THINGS DIFFERENT.
- I DON'T KNOW, MAN.
- BUBS, YOU DON'T
WANT ME TO DO THIS,
I WON'T DO IT.
- I DON'T KNOW.
"BALTIMORE SUN."
A LITTLE BIT OF SUN.
SUN PAPER.
- LOOK, RUPERT,
YOU CAN GO PUBLIC WITH
THIS THING IF YOU WANT,
BUT YOUR SHOP IS GOING
TO COME OUT LOOKING
WORSE FOR LETTING IT
HAPPEN IN THE FIRST PLACE.
- THE BETTER MOVE IS
TO SHUT IT DOWN QUIETLY
AND THEN DEAL WITH
THOSE RESPONSIBLE
THROUGH BACK CHANNELS.
WE'LL BURY THESE GUYS SOFTLY,
AND IN A HOLE SO DEEP
NO ONE WILL EVER GET CLOSE
TO DIGGING THEM UP.
- I CAN SEE THAT.
- COMMISSIONER,
DO YOU AGREE?
- WELL, IT IS A
LITTLE MORE PROBLEMATIC FOR ME.
THE OFFENDERS ARE IN MY SHOP,
ARE THEY NOT?
- CAN I HAVE A WORD WITH YOU
IN PRIVATE, BILL?
- HEY, IF RAWLS ISN'T IN,
I'M NOT EITHER.
- OH, I WOULDN'T WORRY
ABOUT BILL RAWLS.
I BELIEVE HE'S ABOUT TO
HAVE ONE OF THOSE ROAD
TO DAMASCUS MOMENTS....
- I CAN SEE WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING IN THERE.
I CAN SEE THE GEARS
GRINDING IN THAT HEAD
OF YOURS.
YOU'RE THINKING, HEY,
I MIGHT HAVE SOME WOOD
ON CARCETTI HERE.
AFTER ALL, THERE'S NO WAY
THEY CAN PIN THE BLAME
ON ME FOR THIS FIASCO
WITHOUT DOING THEIR
BOY DANIELS, TOO, RIGHT?
YOU'RE THINKING WE'D HAVE
TO FIRE DANIELS
TO FIRE YOU AND
THAT WOULDN'T SIT WELL
GIVEN HOW MUCH WE'VE
ALREADY SOLD DANIELS.
ISN'T THAT WHAT YOU'RE THINKING?
AND SO YOU'RE TELLING
YOURSELF MAYBE THERE'S
A WAY FOR YOU
TO LEVERAGE THIS.
TO GET YOURSELF A FULL
TERM AS COMMISSIONER,
TO DELAY DANIELS A
FEW MORE YEARS IN
EXCHANGE FOR YOU
SHUTTING THE FUCK UP
AND DOING WHAT
YOU'RE TOLD.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, BILL?
YOU'RE NOT FAR OFF.
YOU DO HAVE A LITTLE
LEVERAGE HERE,
BUT JUST A LITTLE.
AND I WOULDN'T OVERPLAY
YOUR HAND.
- HOW WOULD YOU PLAY IT?
- I'D SHUT THE FUCK UP
AND WAIT YOUR TURN,
AND WHEN TOMMY GETS
TO THE STATEHOUSE,
HE BRINGS YOU
WITH HIM TO BE STATE
POLICE SUPERINTENDENT,
BECAUSE WHILE YOU MAY BE
A SHADE TOO WHITE
TO RUN THE BALTIMORE
DEPARTMENT,
YOU'RE JUST ABOUT RIGHT
FOR THE M.S.P.
- I HAVE YOUR WORD?
- AND I HAVE YOURS.
- BACK CHANNEL IS
THE WAY TO GO.
- SEE?
THE POLICE COMMISSIONER
DONE FELL OFF HIS ASS.
- CAN I HELP YOU?
- UM, I NEED TO SEE
MR. PREZBO.
- SOMEONE WILL COME DOWN.
- ARE YOU A STUDENT HERE?
- MS. DONNELLY, IT'S ME,
DUQUAN.
- WELL, IT'S GOOD TO SEE
YOU, DUQUAN,
BUT YOU'RE NOT A STUDENT
HERE SO I CAN'T
LET YOU INSIDE.
- I JUST CAME PAST TO SEE
MR. PREZBO.
- WELL, HE'S TEACHING
RIGHT NOW.
- I KNOW. I CAN WAIT.
- WELL, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO STAY OUTSIDE,
AND AFTER THE BELL,
I'LL TELL
MR. PRYZBYLEWSKI YOU'RE OUT
HERE FOR HIM, OKAY?
- I'M GOING TO SURPRISE
YOU WITH SOMETHING.
- YOU ALREADY HAVE.
- I GOT A TIP FROM
AN INFORMANT ABOUT A
LEAK OUT OF THE GRAND
JURY UNIT,
SAD TO SAY IT'S
CHECKED OUT.
- WE KNOW ABOUT THE LEAK.
- YEAH, BUT DO YOU
KNOW WHO IT IS?
GARY DIPASQUALE.
DECENT ENOUGH GUY,
BUT HE'S GOT A BEAR OF
A GAMBLING PROBLEM
AND A BANK OF
DRUG LAWYERS WHO ARE
WILLING TO PAY FOR
THEIR LOOK-SEES.
TROY SANDERS, MARVIN BRONFMAN,
DENNIS CRAY, SID SILVERSTEIN.
AND THE PICK
OF THE LITTER? MAURICE LEVY.
I KID YOU NOT.
- GARY IS THEIR LEAK?
- HE BROKE RIGHT AWAY.
HE WAS READY TO GIVE IT UP.
HE NEEDED TO.
ONE-PARTY CONSENT
CALL IMPLICATING MAURY LEVY.
- WHERE'S GARY NOW?
- HE WENT UP TO THE SECOND
FLOOR TO HAND
IN HIS LETTER OF
RESIGNATION, THEN HE WENT HOME
TO WAIT FOR THE SWORD
TO DROP.
HE'S OKAY,
HE'S BETTER THAN YOU'D THINK.
YOU KNOW, IF WE CAN TURN
LEVY AND SOME OF THESE
OTHER DRUG LAWYERS,
WE CAN ROUTE THE DRUG
MONEY ALL OVER TOWN.
IT'S SAD BUSINESS,
I KNOW, BUT AT LEAST
WE KNOW THE TRUTH NOW,
RIGHT?
- THE TRUTH, YOU SAY?
- HEY.
- DUQUAN, HELLO.
- SNATCH-POPS.
- HEY!- DAMIEN. YOU LOST
- BUT I SAID SNATCH-POPS.
- I DON'T CARE WHAT YOU SAID.
YOU'RE GONNA BUY HIM
A NEW SANDWICH,
AND PAST THAT, YOU'RE GONNA
GO INSIDE AND ASK MR. WILLIAMS
FOR A BROOM TO CLEAN THAT UP,
YOU UNDERSTAND?
- BUT, MR. P...
- RIGHT NOW, DAMIEN,
OROU'RE MINE FOR ANOTHER
WEEK OF DETENTION.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
ANOTHER WORD.
- LOOKS LIKE YOU GOT
THE HANG OF IT.
- WHAT'S UP WITH YOU, DUQUAN?
- OH, AIN'T NOTHING.
- YOU STILL AT SOUTHWESTERN?
- WELL, I'M, LIKE, NEEDING
A SEMESTER OFF,
YOU KNOW?
I'M OUTDOORS NOW.
AND, UM...
I WAS HOPING MAYBE I
COULD GET WITH YOU
AND BORROW SOME MONEY,
SO I COULD GET A PLACE
AND SOME CLEAN CLOTHES
AND GET MYSELF
SETTLED SO I CAN GO BACK
TO SCHOOL.
- YOU'RE ON THE STREET?
- I MEAN, I GOT SOME PEOPLE
READY TO GIVE ME
A REALLY, REALLY GOOD PLACE
IF I CAN COME UP
WITH SOME MONEY FOR IT.
- HOW MUCH DO YOU NEED?
- COUPLE HUNDRED.
BUT IF YOU COULD GO
ONE FIFTY MORE,
I COULD ENROLL
IN THE G.E.D. PROGRAM
DOWN B.C.C.C.
THEN I COULD GET MY
G.E.D. WITHOUT HAVING
TO GO BACK TO SOUTHWESTERN,
THEN I COULD GET
MY WORK PERMIT.
- I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE ELIGIBLE FOR
A G.E.D. PROGRAM IF
YOU'RE STILL OF AGE
TO ATTEND HIGH SCHOOL,
DUQUAN.
- YEAH, YOU ARE.
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
GIVE ME A COUPLE MINUTES,
I'LL DRIVE YOU DOWN THERE.
AND IF YOU ARE ELIGIBLE,
I'LL WRITE A CHECK
RIGHT TO THE BURSAR'S
OFFICE DOWN THERE.
- NAW, MR. P., YOU AIN'T
GOT TO THROUGH ALL THAT.
BESIDES, I REALLY AIN'T
GOT THE TIME TO
GO DOWN THERE TODAY.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I'M GONNA.
- I CAN DO IT, DUQUAN,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
AND I DON'T EVEN CARE
ABOUT THE MONEY.
BUT UNDERSTAND I'M GONNA
GO DOWN TO B.C.C.C.
IN A FEW DAYS AND FIND
OUT IF YOU'RE ENROLLED.
IF YOU ARE,
I'M GONNA SAY, "GREAT,
"DUQUAN CAN COME PAST
WITH HIS CERTIFICATE
"WHEN HE GETS IT,
AND WE'RE STILL FRIENDS
AND HE CAN STILL
RELY ON ME."
BUT IF YOU AREN'T ENROLLED,
THEN...
WELL, I IMAGINE I'M NOT
GONNA SEE YOU AGAIN,
AM I?
- NO, MR. P.
I'M DEFINITELY GONNA ENROLL.
YOU'LL SEE.
- I'LL GET MY STUFF.
I'LL MEET YOU IN THE LOT
AND WE'LL GO FIND
A BANK MACHINE.
- JAY, ALL I'M SAYING
IS WE'VE RUN DOWN
ALL THE LEADS WE HAD,
ALL THE OFFICE REPORTS
ARE IN AND AT THIS POINT,
BARRING ANY NEW DEVELOPMENTS,
I DON'T NEED ALL
THIS FUCKING MANPOWER.
- FUCK ME, JIMMY.
LAST WEEK YOU WERE CRYING
FOR EVERY SWINGING
DICK YOU COULD GET
YOUR HANDS ON.
- WELL, THE CASE
HAS GONE QUIET.
THERE'S NO RED RIBBONS.
THERE'S NO BODIES.
THERE'S NO DISAPPEARANCES.
THERE'S NOT A FUCKING
WORD ON THE CELL PHONE.
THIS THING'S FUCKING
THING IS USELESS.
- SO WHAT? YOU DON'T WANT
THE WIRETAP EITHER NOW?
- WELL, THE JUDGE GAVE
US 60 DAYS,
ONCE THAT RUNS OUT,
THEN...
- MOTHERFUCKER,
YOU WERE THE ONE WHO WAS
ALL SEMPER FI FOR THIS
SERIAL KILLER
AND NOW YOU'RE FUCKIN'
THE DOG.
- JAY, I'M READY
TO WORK THE CASE.
BUT SHORT OF ANY NEW
LEADS OR DEVELOPMENTS,
WHAT THE FUCK DO YOU
WANT ME TO DO?
I CAN'T MAKE SHIT UP,
CAN I?
IT IS WHAT IT IS.
- IF I SEND THE
SURVEILLANCE TEAMS BACK, JIMMY,
DON'T COME CRYING FOR
MORE MANPOWER TOMORROW.
YOU HEAR?
- SHIT IS LIKE A WAR,
AIN'T IT?
EASY TO GET IN,
HELL TO GET OUT.
- PEARLMAN
KNOWS EVERYTHING. DANIELS, TOO.
THEY FIGURED IT OUT.
- HOW?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- JESUS.
WHAT ARE THEY...
- I DON'T KNOW.
SHE MADE IT CLEAR
IN NO UNCERTAIN TERMS
THERE ARE NOT TO BE ANY
FURTHER HOMELESS KILLINGS.
NOTHING MORE ON THIS
CASE WHATSOEVER.
- DOES SHE KNOW ABOUT MARLO,
THAT OUR CASE--
- SHE KNOWS EVERYTHING.
DANIELS KNOWS.
THEY WENT DOWN TO THE
E.C.U., DIALED UP THE WIRETAP
NUMBER AND UP POP'S
MARLO'S CELL PHONE.
- WHY AREN'T WE FIRED?
WHY AREN'T WE IN FUCKING
BRACELETS?
- I DON'T KNOW.
- OH SHIT, LESTER.
WE GOTTA GET OUTTA HERE.
WE GOTTA THINK THIS
THING THROUGH.
OH, JESUS FUCKING CHRIST.
- LOOK, MEET ME DOWN
AT KAVANAUGH'S IN TEN MINUTES,
ALL RIGHT?
- JIMMY?
- HOW MUCH?
- TWO HUNDRED.
- DAMN, BOY.
TEACHER MUST LOVE
YOUR BLACK ASS.
C'MON WITH IT.
THEY GONNA PUT OUT TESTERS
UP ON POPLAR GROVE.
WE GONNA BE LATE FOR IT.
C'MON, BOY. C'MON.
C'MON.
- DEPUTY...
- TO BE CONTINUED.
- FUCK FUCK FUCKING FUCK.
- AH, WHAT'S THE MATTER?
COTTAGE CHEESE FOR LUNCH
AGAIN THERE, CARL?
- JUST BECAUSE IT HAPPENED
DOESN'T MEAN IT'S NEWS.
THERE'S ALWAYS A
SALMONELLA OUTBREAK SOMEWHERE.
I DON'T SEE WHY WE HAVE TO
COVER THIS ONE...
- WHAT'S THE FIRST RULE
OF REWRITE, SPRY?
- SHOOT IT DOWN.
- DID YOU READ THIS?
WE ARE CREDITING OUR
OWN COVERAGE WITH
CHANGING THE
GOVERNOR'S MIND?
I'M ALREADY TO THE JUMP
AND THERE'S NOT A
QUOTE FROM ANYONE
CREDITING US
WITH ANYTHING OF THE SORT.
- YEAH, THE GUV
IS RESTORING FUNDING, ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S 'CAUSE CARCETTI'S
BEEN BEATING THE SHIT
OUT OF HIM
ON THIS ISSUE.
WE'RE JUST AN AFTERTHOUGHT.
- WHITING CAN SMELL THE
PUBLIC SERVICE PULITZER, HUH?
- SEEMS SO.
- YOU GET A CHANCE YET?
- YEAH, YEAH. I READ IT.
- AND?
- BEAUTIFUL.
NO, NO, NO. I MEAN IT.
YOU GOT SOME REAL JOE MITCHELL
STUFF ON THE PAGE THERE.
REALLY MAKES ME FEEL LIKE
I KNOW THIS GUY AND HIS WORLD.
YOU JUST PULLED IT ALL
THROUGH THE KEYHOLE.
- THANKS, GUS.
- WE GET SOME GOOD ART,
I'M GONNA PUSH FOR
THE SUNDAY FRONT.
- WELL, THE THING IS,
I GOTTA MAKE SURE
THE GUY IS GOOD
WITH IT.
- WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
- THE PART OF THE STORY ABOUT
THE KID STILL BOTHERS HIM,
AND WHEN HE TOLD ME ABOUT IT,
HE WAS JUST TALKING...
- YOU TOLD HIM YOU WERE
WRITING ABOUT HIM, RIGHT?
- I KNOW, BUT...
I'M PUTTING THE GUY'S
LIFE OUT THERE.
I JUST WANNA FEEL
CLEAN ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
- I REMEMBER CLEAN.
- OBVIOUSLY,
THEY'RE NOT IN A HURRY
TO GO PUBLIC
'CAUSE WE AIN'T CUFFED.
- THEY'RE PRETENDING ON THIS
CASE LIKE WE'RE PRETENDING.
WHY?
- CARCETTI.
HE'S EXPOSED ON THIS.
- HOW? JUST BLAME IT ALL ON US,
ON THE DEPARTMENT.
- TO KILL US, THEY'D
HAVE TO KILL RAWLS, DANIELS,
AND HALF THE CHAIN
OF COMMAND.
AND HE MADE THOSE GUYS.
IT'S HIS POLICE DEPARTMENT.
SO HE OPENS HIMSELF
UP RIGHT WHEN HE'S OUT
THERE RUNNING FOR GOVERNOR.
- SO THEY WANT US
TO DO WHAT?
RUN THIS THING DOWN QUIETLY?
THAT'S NO PROBLEM.
- SIX MONTHS FROM NOW,
AFTER THE ELECTION,
THEY MIGHT DECIDE TO OPEN UP
AND GRAND JURY US.
WE COULD STILL GO TO JAIL,
AND IF NOT,
I'D EXPECT TO BE BACK
IN THE PAWN SHOP UNIT
AND YOU, MY BROTHER,
ARE GONNA RIDE THE BOAT.
- SO WHAT?
IT WAS WORTH IT.
WASN'T IT?
- DEPENDS.
ARE THEY GONNA LET
THE CASE AGAINST MARLO
AND HIS PEOPLE STAND,
KNOWING WHAT THEY KNOW?
- WHY WOULDN'T THEY?
IT STILL WORKS ON THE
SEIZURES AND CELL PHONES.
IT WORKS WITHOUT
THE ILLEGAL TAP.
- YEAH, IT DOES.
AND THEY MADE A BIG DEAL
ABOUT DROPPING MARLO.
THEY CALLED THAT PRESS
CONFERENCE
AND LINKED HIM TO
ALL THE BODIES.
- FOR THEM TO DROP
THE CASE NOW...
- YOU KNOW, YOU THINK
ABOUT IT...
WE'VE GOT ALMOST AS MUCH
ON THEM AS THEY DO ON US.
- THAT TOM WOLFE WANNABE
THINKS HE'S GONNA
GET A PHRASE LIKE THAT
PAST ME?
NO FUCKIN' WAY,
MOTHERFUCKER.
- IT'S LIKE A SWEATER WITH
THE THREADS HANGING OFF.
PULL ANY THREAD...
MOSTLY EXAGGERATIONS
AND TOO-PERFECT QUOTES,
SOMETIMES ON-THE-RECORD.
I CALLED SOME OF THEM BACK,
ASKED IF THEY REALLY
SAID THOSE THINGS.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE CITY
HOUSING COMMISSIONER TOLD ME
ABOUT THE QUOTES IN
THE FLIPPING STORY?
- HMM?
- HE WISHED HE'D SAID
SOME OF THEM,
BUT THAT HE'D NEVER BEEN
THAT SMART IN HIS LIFE.
SOMEONE TAKES
THE TIME TO...
RE-REPORT THIS STUFF,
IT'LL GET UGLY.
WHAT'RE YOU GONNA DO?
- I DON'T KNOW, ROBERT.
I DON'T KNOW.
- KEEP MY NAME OUT OF IT.
- NO BAIL.
THEY'RE CLAIMING A
PROPENSITY FOR VIOLENCE AND
WITNESS INTIMIDATION AT
THE BAIL REVIEW,
TRYING TO HAVE YOU HELD
AS THE KINGPIN.
- THEY CAN DO THAT?
- THEY CAN TRY.
DEPENDS ON WHICH
JUDGE THEY DRAW.
- SO THEY AIN'T GOT NO
BAIL FOR CHRIS, RIGHT?
I MEAN, HE GOT THE
MURDER WARRANT.
- MONK NEITHER.
TOO MUCH WEIGHT IN HIS CAR
AND HE'S ON PAROLE FROM
THE '04 CHARGE.
BEST I COULD DO WAS SPRING
MR. WAGSTAFF ON 300,000.
- HE SHOW THAT KIND
OF MONEY?
- PUT UP HIS UNCLE'S HOUSE
ON SURETY BOND
FOR A THIRD OF IT.
BONDSMAN IS FRONTING
THE REST ON A FAKE LIEN.
RIGHT NOW, THE IMPORTANT
THING IS NOT BAIL,
THE IMPORTANT THING
IS THIS...
I NEED YOU TO TELL ME WHO
ELSE KNEW YOUR CLOCK CODE.
- I TOLD YOU.
ME, CHEESE, MONK, CHRIS
AND THE SUPPLY. THAT'S IT.
- NO ONE ELSE.
- NO ONE ELSE EVEN HAD
MY CELL NUMBER.
EXCEPT YOU.
WHAT?
- THERE'S A LIE
IN HERE SOMEWHERE.
- I AIN'T LYIN'.
- I DON'T MEAN YOU.
LOOK, THE POLICE SAY
A SOURCE TOLD THEM
THAT YOU WERE RE-UPPING
ON THE DAY,
AND WORD OF THAT
MIGHT HAVE SLIPPED OUT.
THAT'S POSSIBLE.
I MEAN, IF YOU WERE
WHOLESALING ALL OVER TOWN...
BUT THEY ONLY GRAB YOUR
CELLS WHEN THEY ARREST YOU
AND THEN THEY HAVE TO
GO GET WARRANTS
BEFORE THEY CAN LOOK AT
THE PHOTOS ON THE PHONES.
AND IT'S ONLY WHEN THEY
GET TO THE PHOTOS
AND BREAK THE CODE
THAT THEY HAVE ENOUGH TO
TYPE A CHARGING DOCUMENT
FOR YOU OR CHRIS, RIGHT?
I MEAN, YOU AREN'T
CAUGHT WITH DRUGS.
BUT THEY HAD THE ARREST
WARRANTS ON BOTH OF YOU
WITHIN A COUPLE HOURS.
WHICH MEANS THAT THEY BROKE
THE CODE ALMOST INSTANTLY,
IN NO TIME AT ALL.
- THEY WIRETAPPED ME.
- MY INVESTIGATOR
THINKS SO.
BUT HE SAYS HE DOESN'T
KNOW FOR SURE WHICH
UNIT RAN THE TAP,
OR WHO MANNED IT.
IT DOESN'T ADD UP.
- YOU GETTIN' OUT.
YOU AIN'T.
YOU HIT THE STREETS,
YOU ROUND UP AS MUCH
MUSCLE AS POSSIBLE
AND GET THAT BOY.
- HE DID SNOOP CUZ
HE KNEW WE WAS ON HIM.
- HE KNEW WE WAS ON HIM CUZ
HE THE ONE TALKED ABOUT
THE DAMN RE-UP.
GET YOUR SHIT TOGETHER,
MAN.
THE BONDSMAN CAME IN
WITH LEVY.
- A'IGHT. I'M ON IT.
- HEY, MAN, YOU GOT A DOLLAR?
C'MON.
- HEY, PAL.
HEY.
PAL, YOU ALL RIGHT?
- OKAY, HERE IT COMES...
THE DREADED CRAB CLAW.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN CRAB CLAW GOES...
IT'S ALL CRAB TONIGHT...
- NO CRAB CLAW!
- YES, CRAB CLAW!
YEAH!
CRAB CLAW DOES IT AGAIN.
SIX!
SIX AND I'M OUT...
YEAH?
WHERE?
YOU'RE FUCKING KIDDING ME.
IT'S MORE BULL...
IT'S BOGUS, JAY.
I'M TELLING YOU...
OKAY.
I GOTTA GO.
I HAVE TO KEEP
RUNNING THE STRING OUT.
I HAVE NO CHOICE.
- YOU SAID
THE BOSSES KNOW.
- YEAH.
SOME DO, SOME DON'T.
THE ONES THAT DO
WANT US TO KEEP PRETENDING.
WE STOP PRETENDING,
THEN...
LISTEN, WE'LL FINISH
THIS TOMORROW NIGHT, OKAY?
I'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I MEAN, PUTTIN' MY SHIT
IN THE STREETS, HUH?
- WELL, IT'S YOU.
HE'S GOT YOU.
- YEAH, WELL...
- I MEAN HE'S GOT
WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT.
THE GUY LIKES YOU,
THAT SHOWS THROUGH.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW,
HE'S SAYING THIS GIVING
BACK THAT YOU'RE DOING,
HE'S PUTTING
THAT UP AGAINST SHERROD.
AND HE AIN'T LETTIN' YOU
OFF THE HOOK FOR SHIT, BUT...
HE'S JUST PUTTIN'
IT ALL OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW, THE GOOD
AND THE BAD.
- KNOW WHAT?
THE BAD DON'T BOTHER ME
TO HAVE OUT THERE.
SHIT, I KNOW THE BAD.
I AIN'T LYIN' TO NO ONE
ABOUT THE BAD.
- SCARED OF SOMEBODY
CALLIN' YOU GOOD?
- A LOT OF FOLKS
VOLUNTEER PLACES.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
SHARE AT MEETINGS.
PLENTY OF MOTHERFUCKERS
WAKE UP EVERY DAY
AND NOT GET HIGH.
MAN MAKIN' ME SOUND SPECIAL
FOR DOIN' WHAT THE FUCK
I NEED TO BE DOIN'.
- READ IT, SUCKA.
- "YOU CAN HOLD BACK FROM
THE SUFFERING OF THE WORLD,
"YOU HAVE FREE
PERMISSION TO DO SO,
"AND IT IS IN ACCORDANCE
WITH YOUR NATURE,
"BUT PERHAPS THIS VERY
HOLDING BACK IS THE ONE
SUFFERING YOU COULD
HAVE AVOIDED."
FAN-ZEE KAFKA.
WHO'S HE?
- SOME WRITER.
- YOU READ HIS BOOKS?
- FUCK NO.
BUT YOU REMEMBER FLUBBER?
HE HANDED THAT TO ME
THE NIGHT THAT
HE HAD ME START LEADING
THE SAINT MARTIN MEETING.
I KEPT IT EVER SINCE.
- WHAT IT MEAN TO YOU?
- YOU WANT THESE?
- YEAH, MY MAN SAY HE
NEED IT BACK AND
NOT TO MAKE ANY COPIES.
HE SAYIN' HE AIN'T
SUPPOSED TO SHOW IT
TO ME BEFORE IT GOES
IN THE PAPER.
I MEAN, IF I LET HIM.
- YOU GONNA?
- THANKS FOR THE CRABS.
- YEP.
- GRAY VAN.
YOU GET THE TAG?
- I COULDN'T SEE IT
FROM WHERE I WAS.
- DESCRIBE THE DRIVER.
- WHITE. SIX FOOT.
NOT HEAVY,
NOT SKINNY EITHER.
- CLOTHES?
- NOTHING I NOTICED.
KINDA NON-DESCRIPT.
- NON-DESCRIPT?
- I WAS SURPRISED, I GUESS.
I JU THOUGHT, WHOA,
WHAT'S HE DOING?
- FUNNY IT BEIN'
YOU TO SEE THIS.
- IT'S WEIRD. IF AN INTERVIEW
DOESN'T RUN LATE,
I'M NOT EVEN HERE TONIGHT.
YOU MIND IF I GET INSIDE?
I GOTTA CHECK IN WITH MY DESK.
YOU NEED ANYTHING ELSE,
YOU GOT MY NUMBER.
- YEAH.
- THAT GUY'S AN ASSHOLE.
THIS SMOKEHOUND
CAN'T REMEMBER A THING.
ONLY MOTHERFUCKER HE
REMEMBERS MESSIN'
WITH HIM IS THE FELLA
THAT FOUND HIM.
WHATEVER HAPPENED BEFORE
THAT IS ANYONE'S GUESS.
- HEY.
SOMEONE TRY TO KIDNAP YOU?
DRAG YOU INTO A VAN?
- OK.
- WHO WAS TRYING TO HURT YOU?
- MY FATHER.
BUT HE WAS A DRUNK.
- DETECTIVE,
THERE'S A VAGRANT OVER HERE
- WHAT DID YOU SEE, FELLA?
- McNULTY?
JOHNNY WEAVER. TACTICAL.
- FUCK YOU.
WHY DIDN'T YOU SAY SO?
- J.W.
TRYIN' TO KEEP YOUR COVER,
HUH?
IT'S BETTER FOR EVERYONE
DOWN HERE THINKS I'M
ONE OF THE REGULARS,
RIGHT?
ANYWAY, WHAT'S THE
RUCKUS WITH PETEY?
-THE DRUNK?
- YEAH.
SUN REPORTER SAYS HE'S
GOING INTO HIS BUILDING,
HE SEES A GUY TRYING
TO DRAG HIM INTO
A GREY VAN.
IT'S BULLSHIT, RIGHT?
- YEAH. PETEY WAS LAYIN'
THERE FORTY-FIVE MINUTES
BEFORE THAT PREPPY COCKSUCKER
EVEN PARKS HIS CAR.
- THANKS.
- NO PROBLEM.
HEY, GIMME A DOLLAR,
MAKE IT LOOK RIGHT.
- THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
- WHAT ABOUT THE REPORTER?
YOU COULD CHARGE
FALSE STATEMENT, YOU KNOW.
- YOU LOCK UP EVERY LIAR,
THERE'S NO ROOM IN B.D.C.
FOR ANYONE ELSE, RIGHT?
MORE TROUBLE THAN IT'S WORTH.
JAY, IT'S HORSESHIT.
I'M GOIN' HOME.
YEAH.
- BROUGHT HOME SOME CRABS.
- I ALREADY MADE DINNER.
- PUT 'EM IN THE FRIDGE.
COLD FOR LUNCH TOMORROW
IF YOU LIKE.
I CAN'T EAT 'EM ALL.
- WE DON'T RUN THIS SHIT,
ESPECIALLY NOT OFF THE FRONT.
- I SAW WHAT I SAW.
- ALMA IS ON THE PHONE
WITH POLICE P.I.O.
AND THEY ARE TELLING US
ON THE RECORD AND OFF
THAT THEY ARE
DISCOUNTING ANY REPORT OF
A POSSIBLE ABDUCTION.
- THAT MAY BE.
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN
THEY'RE DOING THEIR JOB,
AND IT DOESN'T MEAN
WE SHOULDN'T BE--
- OUR JOB IS TO REPORT
THE NEWS,
NOT TO MANUFACTURE IT.
- NICE.
- I KNOW THAT THEY'RE
JEALOUS OF HOW MUCH PLAY
HIS STORIES GET,
BUT THE TRUTH IS...
- WE CANNOT RUN THIS SHIT.
- ARE YOU SUGGESTING THAT
SCOTT MADE ANY OF THIS UP?
- YOU EVER NOTICE THAT
THE GUYS WHO DO THAT...
THE BLAIRS, THE GLASSES,
THE KELLEYS.
THEY ALWAYS START
WITH SOMETHING SMALL,
YOU KNOW, JUST A LITTLE
QUOTE THAT THEY CLEAN UP,
AND THEN, THEN IT'S
A WHOLE ANECDOTE,
AND PRETTY SOON THEY'RE SEEING
SOME AMAZING SHIT.
THEY'RE THE LUCKY ONES
WHO JUST HAPPEN
TO BE STANDING ON THE
RIGHT STREET CORNER
IN TEL AVIV WHEN
THE PIZZA JOINT BLOWS UP
AND THE HUMAN HEAD ROLLS
DOWN THE STREET
WITH THE EYES STILL BLINKING.
- THOSE PICTURES WERE
SENT TO HIM.
THE POLICE HAVE CONFIRMED...
- IT ALWAYS STARTS
WITH SOMETHING TRUE,
SOMETHING CONFIRMED.
BUT THEN YOU'VE GOT A
SON OF A BITCH WHO JUST
HAPPENS TO BE WALKING
IN THE GUILFORD ENTRANCE
WHEN THE MYSTERIOUS
GRAY VAN COMES--
- GUS, THIS HAS GOTTEN
PERSONAL BETWEEN YOU AND SCOTT
AND IT'S AFFECTING
YOUR JUDGMENT.
I'M MOVING THE STORY
THROUGH THE STATE DESK.
YOU SHOULD GO HOME,
THINK THIS THROUGH.
WE'LL TALK IN THE MORNING.
- MAYBE YOU WIN A
PULITZER WITH THIS STUFF.
AND MAYBE YOU GOTTA
GIVE IT BACK.
- IT'S IN MY NOTES, GUS.
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED.
EVERYTHING THAT GUY SAID
WHEN I GOT TO HIM.
EVERY LAST WORD IS
IN MY NOTES.
- HOME EARLIER THAN
I THOUGHT.
- YEAH. HOME.
- HE HIT AGAIN.
- WHO DID?
- SERIAL KILLER.
- GET A GRIP, MOTHERFUCKER.
- YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME?
CHECK OUT HIS LEFT WRIST.
- YOU FUCKIN' WITH ME AGAIN,
BUNK?
- COPYCAT.
CALL McNULTY.
GET HIM DOWN HERE.
- RONNIE.
- MAURY.
- BEEN GOING OVER THE
CHARGING DOCUMENTS ON THE
PARTLOW-STANFIELD DRUG ARRESTS.
PROBLEMATIC TO SAY THE LEAST.
- HOW SO?
- THEY GRAB THE PHONES
AND MINUTES LATER
THEY'VE CRACKED AN
ELABORATE CODE THAT
IMPLICATES EVERYONE.
NO ONE'S THAT BRILLIANT.
NOT IN THE B.P.D.
ANYWAY.
- YOU DON'T KNOW
LESTER FREAMON.
- I KNOW WHAT I KNOW.
AND THIS FEELS TO ME
LIKE AN ILLEGAL WIRETAP.
YOUR GUYS WERE UP ON THOSE
PHONES AND TRACKING
MY CLIENTS LONG BEFORE
THEY WENT NEAR ANY DRUGS.
- UNTRUE.
- WE GET INTO DISCOVERY AND
I'M GOING TO HAVE NO PROBLEM
KNOCKING DOWN THAT BULLSHIT
ABOUT A SOURCE OF INFORMATION.
AND MY SOURCES AROUND HERE
TELL ME THAT WITH ALL
THE BUDGET CUTBACKS,
THE ONLY WIRETAP
YOU ALL HAVE
HAD UP THIS YEAR
HAS BEEN ON
THE HOMELESS KILLER THING.
WHATEVER ELSE YOU'RE
RUNNING IS ILLEGAL.
- SOURCES?
TITLE THREES ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE SECRET, MAURY.
ARE YOU SAYING YOU HAVE
A SOURCE OF INFORMATION
INSIDE THE COURTHOUSE?
- IT'S A FIGURE OF SPEECH.
WHAT I'M SAYING IS THAT
THERE'S SHIT IN THE
BLOOD OF YOUR CASE.
AND IF YOU WAIT UNTIL THIS
GOES PAST INDICTMENTS,
I'M GONNA RUN WILD WITH IT.
WE SHOULD TALK.
OUT OF COURT.
- OH, FUCK ME.
- IS IT ENOUGH?
DO YOU HAVE ENOUGH?
- IT HAS TO BE.
IT SHOULD BE.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T LOOK
AT EVERYTHING THAT ROBERT
FOUND AT THE PATTERN,
AND NOT SEE WHAT THIS
FUCKING GUY'S ABOUT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
I KNOW THAT.
WHAT YOU DON'T THINK SO?
- I THINK THAT IF YOU DO THIS,
THESE SON OF A BITCHES
WILL DO YOU.
- COME.
- SORRY. THERE'S BEEN ANOTHER
HOMELESS MURDER.
SOUTH BALTIMORE.
- CAREFUL, GUS.
I CAN'T PROTECT YOU.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
- NO FUCKING WAY.
- DEAD FOR A WHILE.
AND I CAN ASSUME, JIMMY,
FROM THE FACT THAT
THE RIBBON AIN'T RED
AND THE SIMPLE FACT
THAT YOU DON'T NEED
ANOTHER BODY BECAUSE
MARLO IS LOCKED UP...
- I GOT NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS.
- WONDERFUL.
WE'VE ELIMINATED
ONE SUSPECT.
YOU SEE WHAT YOU
STARTED HERE?
- THE BOSSES ARE GONNA
TOSS IT BACK TO YOU,
NO DOUBT.
- THE BOSSES KNOW
IT'S BULLSHIT.
- WHAT?
- DANIELS KNOWS.
PEARLMAN, TOO.
- HOW THE FUCK YOU...
HOW MUCH LONGER DOES THIS...
- CAN YOU GIVE US A MINUTE?
- YOU TURNING THE WORLD
UPSIDE DOWN WITH YOUR BULLSHIT.
HOW ARE YOU NOT IN JAIL?
- I DON'T KNOW.
THE LIE'S SO BIG, PEOPLE
CAN LIVE WITH IT, I GUESS.
- JESUS FUCKING CHRIST, JIMMY.
I TOLD YOU.
I FUCKIN' TOLD YOU IT WAS
GOING TO COME TO THIS.
YOU PLAYED WITH FIRE,
DIDN'T YOU?
AND NOW WE'RE ALL
GETTING BURNED...
- REPORTING LIVE
FROM SOUTH BALTIMORE
WHERE POLICE HAVE FOUND THE BODY
OF WHAT APPEARS TO BE
ANOTHER HOMELESS MAN.
THIS ONE KILLED AND LEFT
IN A VACANT LOT...
...SHORT WHILE AGO
HAVE REFUSED SO FAR...
- DID SOMEBODY NOT
GET THE MESSAGE?
- YOU'RE NOT KILLING
THEM YOURSELF, McNULTY.
AT LEAST ASSURE ME OF THAT.
AND THE ONE YOU DISAPPEARED.
- HE'S OKAY, LAST I CHECKED.
- GOOD. THAT'S A START...
I GUESS.
- I THOUGHT YOU GOT
A MESSAGE.
- COPYCAT.
I GOT NOTHING ON THIS ONE.
- JESUS.
- HOW DID YOU DO IT?
HOW DID YOU GET 'EM BY
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER?
- SOME WERE REAL AND
I JUST LINKED 'EM
WITH THE RIBBONS.
SOME I JUKED AS
STRANGLE JOBS.
IF IT MATTERS, I KNOW NOW...
- FUCK WHAT YOU KNOW NOW.
THIS WAS ALL FOR MONEY,
McNULTY?
YOU COULDN'T LIVE
WITHOUT THE O.T.?
- THE STANFIELD CASE.
IT WAS THAT.
- I KNOW WHERE IT WENT,
BUT YOU GOT PAID, TOO.
YOU AND FREAMON AND
MAYBE A DOZEN OTHER GUYS.
- IT WASN'T ABOUT THE MONEY.
- DOWN THE ROAD,
WHEN WE SETTLE ON THIS--
AND WE WILL SETTLE ON THIS--
I DON'T EXPECT ANY OF YOU
WILL EVER SEE ANOTHER HOUR
OF O.T. AGAIN.
I DON'T EXPECT ANY OF
YOU WILL BE DOING
POLICE WORK EVER AGAIN.
AND THE ONLY REASON
THIS ISN'T BEFORE A
GRAND JURY RIGHT NOW
IS BECAUSE OUR MAYOR
CAN'T LIVE WITH THAT.
OH, YEAH.
THE MAYOR KNOWS YOUR NAME.
- SO THIS IS YOUR LAST CASE.
WORK IT.
- IF YOU'RE HALF THE
DETECTIVE YOU THINK YOU ARE,
YOU'LL PUT THIS ONE DOWN
FAST AND TAKE US ALL
OFF THE HOOK.
THE LONGER THIS GOES ON,
THE WORSE THE PAYBACK'S
GONNA BE.
- BUT WHAT DOES HE
REALLY KNOW?
- WHAT HE KNOWS NOW ISN'T
HALF OF WHAT HE'LL LEARN
WHEN WE GET TO DISCOVERY.
THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO
PRODUCE A CREDIBLE SOURCE
OF INFORMATION...
- THEY DON'T HAVE TO IF
IT'S NOT A REGISTERED C.I.
A SOURCE OF INFORMATION
IS ONLY--
- IF HE CAN RAISE DOUBTS
IN A JUDGE'S MIND,
WE COULD BE COMPELLED
TO REVEAL OUR SOURCE.
AT THAT POINT,
WE'RE GIVING UP THE WIRETAP.
- AND HE GETS THE PAPERWORK
FROM THE PHONE COMPANY...
- WHICH HAS STANFIELD'S
NUMBER ON IT.
- GOD.
- THE ONLY THING WE
CAN DO IS BARTER.
- THEN BARTER.
THIS CAN'T GO TO COURT.
- WE DO HAVE SOME LEVERAGE.
- WHAT?
- LET'S JUST SAY MR. LEVY
HAS PROBLEMS OF HIS
OWN TO DEAL WITH.
- MAKE THIS GO AWAY...
AND THE MAYOR WILL NOT
FORGET THAT YOU DID SO.
NOR WILL I.
JIMMY, ASS UP AN'
HELP WITH THIS.
- SHIT IS FUNKY.
- AW, MAN, WE SHOULD TAKE
THIS INTO THE BOX.
- WHERE'S THE
POCKET CONTENTS?
- WE HAVE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE REPORT
OF THE KIDNAPPING...
- THOSE TWO BAGS THERE.
- YES, MA'AM.
WELL, THAT WOULD SEEM TO
BE THE NEWSPAPER'S PROBLEM.
I GET ANOTHER FUCKING
CALL ABOUT A GRAY VAN
AND I'M BURNING THAT
FUCKING NEWSPAPER BUILDING
TO THE GROUND.
- HUH.
- WHAT?
- YOUR HOMELESS GUY
FROM DAYS AGO.
WHAT WAS IN HIS POCKETS?
- BULLSHIT.
- YOU GOT BUSINESS CARDS?
- YEAH, BUT EVERY CARD
HAS AN ALIBI.
- LET ME SEE.
- I THOUGHT WE
WERE DONE WITH THIS.
SO, WHERE YOU GOING WITH THIS?
- MOTHERFUCKER,
YOU AIN'T THAT GOOD.
- McNULTY,
WHAT'S UP WITH THIS?
- YOU OKAY, GUS?
- HMMM?
YEAH, I'M GREAT.
WHAT?
ALMA, WHAT'S UP?
- IT'S EMPTY.
- WHAT'S EMPTY?
- THE PAD HE WAVED AT YOU,
SAYING IT WAS ALL
FILLED WITH NOTES.
IT'S EMPTY. EVERY PAGE.
- THANKS.
- WHAT THE FUCK
IS THAT ABOUT?
UH-OH.
ALMA, T.V. HAS POLICE
ON A SWEEP OF THE HOMELESS
UNDER HANOVER STREET.
- I'LL GET RIGHT
TO THE POINT.
- PLEASE DO.
- MAURY, HEY.
- YEAH, HI.
- YOU HAVE STANFIELD, RIGHT?
HE'S YOUR CLIENT?
- YEAH, HIM AND HIS PEOPLE.
- WELL, I HAVE SOME STUFF,
STRAIGHT FROM THE GRAND JURY
THAT YOU'RE GONNA WANNA
SEE SOONER RATHER THAN LATER.
- IS THIS A TITLE
THREE CASE?
- YOU'RE GONNA
FIND IT INTERESTING, I PROMISE.
- ALL RIGHT.
WHEN CAN YOU MEET?
- TOMORROW, AFTER WORK.
SAME MONEY, RIGHT?
- YEAH, THE MONEY'S THE SAME.
- GOOD.
- WE CAN GRAND JURY
GARY DIPASQUALE TOMORROW,
ALONG WITH THAT
ONE-PARTY CONSENT CALL.
OR...HERE'S THE DEAL.
NO COURT TRIALS.
PARTLOW PLEADS TO ALL OF
THE BODIES IN THE VACANTS
AND TAKES LIFE,
NO PAROLE.
WE'D WANT THE
SECOND SHOOTER TOO,
BUT PEARSON'S
BEYOND THAT NOW.
METCALF AND WAGSTAFF PLEAD
TO POSSESSION WITH INTENT.
STANFIELD TAKES TEN YEARS
ON CONSPIRACY.
- YOU'RE BLACKMAILING
AN OFFICER OF THE COURT.
THE MOMENT YOU CAME IN HERE
AND OFFERED THAT QUID PRO QUO
YOU WERE GUILTY OF
OBSTRUCTION OF JUSTICE.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
I COULD GET SIX TO
EIGHT YEARS.
AND FOR BRIBERY OF A STATE'S
ATTORNEY AND THE VIOLATION
OF GRAND JURY SECRECY,
YOU COULD SEE TEN TO TWELVE.
I'LL BE OUT A COUPLE
YEARS BEFORE YOU, MAURY.
YOU COME HOME,
FIRST ROUND'S ON ME, I GUESS.
- SO YOU'LL LET ME WALK
TO KEEP THIS CASE OUT OF
OPEN COURT?
THAT FILE MUST BE DIRTY
AS HELL. HUH?
THE CONSPIRACY CHARGE
ON STANFIELD FALLS
WITHOUT THE CELL PHONES,
AND YOU AND I BOTH KNOW
THAT IF SOMEONE DOES
SOME DIGGING,
THEY'RE GONNA FIND AN
ILLEGAL WIRETAP AND
YOU'RE GONNA LOSE
THE PHONES.
- EVERHART, TWO-SEVENTY-FOUR,
MARYLAND FOUR-FIFTY-NINE.
OR CECCOLINI,
FOUR-THIRTY-FIVE,
U.S. TWO-SIXTY-EIGHT.
LYING COPS DON'T
AUTOMATICALLY KILL A CASE.
- BUT THAT'S A LOT OF RISK
ON APPEAL...
AND A LOT OF DIRT FOR
YOUR OFFICE TO SHOW.
NO.
YOU'RE SCARED
OF THE LIGHT.
PARTLOW TAKES HIS CHANCES
ON THE LEGIT MURDER CHARGE ONLY.
THE CONSPIRACY COUNT
GOES AND STANFIELD
AND THE REST WALK.
- STANFIELD WALKS.
BUT THE CASE GOES ON
THE STET DOCKET,
NOT DISMISSED OUTRIGHT.
AND ALTHOUGH I CAN TELL
YOU THERE ARE PEOPLE
IN THIS CITY WHO CAN'T
TOLERATE A SCANDAL AT
THIS PARTICULAR MOMENT,
THAT DYNAMIC CHANGES
AFTER NOVEMBER.
- THE ELECTIONS...
- AFTER NOVEMBER,
NO ONE IS GOING TO CARE
AS MUCH ABOUT SHOWING DIRT.
IF CARCETTI WINS,
HE'S IN ANNAPOLIS.
IF HE LOSES,
HE'S AN INCUMBENT MAYOR
WHO CAN TAKE A HIT OR TWO.
SO YOU TELL
MR. STANFIELD THAT THIS
IS HIS ONLY WINDOW.
PARTLOW PLEADS TO ALL
THE MURDERS
AND BOTH LIEUTENANTS
PLEAD TO THE DRUGS.
THEN STANFIELD RETIRES.
HE'S DONE.
WE EVEN GET THE SCENT OF HIM
ON THE STREET EVER AGAIN,
THIS CASE COMES OFF STET
AND GOES TO TRIAL.
AND IF WE HAVE TO PUT
A FEW COPS IN JAIL
RIGHT BEHIND HIM, SO BE IT.
WE'LL BRING THE EVIDENCE
AND TAKE A HIT.
YOUR CLIENT WALKS
AWAY NOW...
OR THE BOTH OF YOU
DON'T WALK AT ALL.
- LET'S GO. GET UP.
- THAT'S MINE.
- IT'S YOURS. I KNOW.
- DO YOU HAVE A CARD?
THAT'S NOT A CARD.
- WE MET BEFORE,
YOU REMEMBER?
- LIAR.
BLACK LIAR.
- WHY'D YOU KILL
YOUR FRIEND?
- HE DRINKS...
HE'S ALWAYS DRINKING.
- BUT YOU PUT A
RIBBON AROUND HIS WRIST.
LIKE THE OTHERS.
- YEAH.
- DID YOU SEE THAT
ON TELEVISION?
THE RIBBON ON THE WRIST?
DID YOU HEAR ABOUT THAT
FROM OTHER PEOPLE?
WHY'D YOU DO THE THING
WITH THE RIBBON?
- NOBODY UNDERSTANDS.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I ALWAYS KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING TO DO...
BEFORE I DO IT. OKAY?
I ALWAYS KNOW WHAT
I'M GOING TO DO.
- DID YOU KILL THE OTHERS?
DID YOU KILL ALL OF THEM?
- EVERY ONE OF THEM.
I DID IT BECAUSE I KNEW
I WAS GOING TO DO IT.
I'VE KILLED MILLIONS.
OKAY?
AND THEY ALL KILLED ME.
- SO YOU DID ALL
THE MURDERS, HUH?
- YOU'RE A COWARD.
I CAN TELL.
HEY, DO YOU HAVE
A CARD?
- JIMMY, REPORTER'S IN THERE
WAITING FOR A PHOTO ARRAY.
- WHAT?
JAY, HE'S BULLSHIT.
- I KNOW HE IS.
BUT THE NEWSPAPER MADE
SUCH A FUSS THE MAJOR
WANTS US TO JERK HIM OFF,
JUST TO SAY WE DID.
- HEY, DETECTIVE.
UM...
- NO GRAY VAN EITHER.
- W-WHAT...
- HE DOESN'T HAVE A GREY VAN.
NO GRAY VAN.
AND HE DIDN'T CALL YOU
ON THE PHONE EITHER, DID HE?
HE DIDN'T CALL YOU
THE FIRST TIME
AND HE DIDN'T CALL
YOU THE SECOND.
I DID THAT.
YEW MORTIFY ME
IN FRONTA MY FATHA...
AND THOSE PICTURES YOU GOT.
I TOOK THOSE.
AND THE MISSING GUY?
HE'S MY SECOND COUSIN.
WE SENT HIM UP TO ATLANTIC CITY
WITH A ROLL OF QUARTERS.
AND YOU KNOW WHY I CAN
TELL YOU ALL THIS?
BECAUSE,
YOU LYIN' MOTHERFUCKER,
YOU'RE AS FULL
OF SHIT AS I AM,
AND YOU'VE GOT TO LIVE
WITH IT AND PLAY IT OUT
FOR AS LONG AS IT GOES.
RIGHT?
TRAPPED IN THE SAME LIE.
ONLY DIFFERENCE IS
I KNOW WHY I DID IT...
AND FUCK IF I CAN
FIGURE OUT WHAT IT GETS YOU
IN THE END.
BUT HEY, I AIN'T PART
OF YOUR TRIBE.
- YOU'RE NOT SERIOUS...
YOU CAN'T...
- NO.
NO, I'M A FUCKING JOKE...
AND SO ARE YOU.
NOW GET THE FUCK
OUT OF HERE.
- YOU WALK.
CHRIS EATS THE MURDERS,
EVERY LAST ONE,
TAKES LIFE WITH NO PAROLE.
- NO PAROLE?
- NO SHOT.
BUT THEY'VE GOT HIM COLD
ON THE ONE WITH THE D.N.A.
CAN YOU SELL THAT?
IS CHRIS LOYAL?
- YEAH.
AS LONG AS I TAKE CARE
OF HIS PEOPLE.
- CHEESE AND MONK ARE
LOOKING AT UP TO TWENTY
FOR THE DRUGS.
BUT THERE'S GONNA BE NO
ASSETS INVESTIGATION
AND YOU COME HOME
WITH ALL YOUR MONEY.
- WHY THEY LETTING ME WALK?
- THEY DON'T WANT TO,
BUT THERE'S SOME SHIT
IN THEIR CASE AND
THEY'D RATHER NOT SHOW
IT IN COURT.
BUT HERE'S THE RUB:
IF YOU STAY IN THE GAME,
THEY WILL.
THEY DEFINITELY WILL.
RIGHT NOW, WITH AN
ELECTION GOING ON,
THEY'RE WILLING TO
GIVE YOU A BUY.
BUT AFTER NOVEMBER,
IF THEY EVEN THINK
YOU'RE STILL A PLAYER,
THEY CAN TAKE THIS CASE
DOWN OFF THE SHELF AND
THE SHIT IN THE CASE
MIGHT NOT BE ENOUGH
TO KEEP YOU FREE.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
- GIVE UP THE CROWN.
- WELL, THAT'S THE DEAL,
KIDDO.
THERE'S NOT A LAWYER WHO
COULD GET BETTER FOR YOU.
- HOW'D THAT GO, BOSS?
- KIDDO, YOU ARE A GOLDMINE
TO ME. YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU'VE TAKEN THIS LAW FIRM
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
- ME?
- YOU DON'T TIP ME TO
THAT BAD WIRETAP,
I'VE GOT ALL KINDS
OF TROUBLE.
BUT NOW, IF MARLO
TAKES THE DEAL,
HE'S GONNA GET A WALK
AFTER BEING CHARGED
IN A MULTIMILLION
DOLLAR DRUG SEIZURE.
THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN
VERY OFTEN,
AND WHEN IT DOES HAPPEN,
THE NAME AND NUMBER
OF THE DEFENSE ATTORNEY
GOES IN THE FRONT
POCKET OF EVERY RESPECTABLE
DRUG TRAFFICKER.
YOU'RE A GENIUS FOR WHAT
YOU BROUGHT ME ON THIS.
- I'M JUST DOIN'
WHAT I DO, RIGHT?
YOU NEED TO KNOW SOMETHING,
ALL YOU GOTTA DO IS ASK.
THAT'S WHAT A DETECTIVE IS,
RIGHT?
- HERE.
YOU SHOULD COME OVER
FOR DINNER TONIGHT.
YVETTE'S MAKING BRISKET.
- YOUR HOUSE?
- YOU'RE MISHPUCHA NOW.
- IF YOU SAY SO.
- IT'S DOWN.
- NOT THAT THIS THING
IS EVER GOING TO TRIAL.
GUY HAS N.C.R. WRITTEN
ALL OVER HIM.
- CAN'T ARGUE.
A PADDED ROOM AT CLIFTON T.
PERKINS IS DEFINITELY
CALLED FOR.
- HE GO FOR ALL OF THEM?
- NO, SIR.
JUST THE LAST TWO.
- HE DENY THE OTHERS?
- HE AIN'T EXACTLY
DENYING ANYTHING IN THERE.
I MEAN, HE'LL COP TO
ANYTHING WE DAMN PLEASE...
- THEN GO BACK AND GET IT.
- EXCUSE ME?
IF HE'S N.C.R.,
WHAT THE FUCK IS
THE DIFFERENCE IF HE
COPS TO TWO OR SIX?
EITHER WAY, THEY TIE HIS
ARMS AND FEED HIM GREEN JELL-O.
- SIR, HE DID THE LAST TWO.
- MOTHERFUCKER,
YOU ARE A CUNT HAIR AWAY
FROM INDICTMENT AND YOU
SEE FIT TO ARGUE WITH ME?
- I DID WHAT I DID.
I KNOW.
AND NOW, I'M STANDING
RESPONSIBLE FOR TWO FRESH
MURDERS.
I KNOW WHAT
I'VE DONE HERE.
BUT I'M NOT DOING THIS.
- THIS IS OVER.
AND ALL OF OUR CITIZENS
CAN REST SOUNDLY
IN THE KNOWLEDGE THAT
THE MAN RESPONSIBLE
HAS BEEN APPREHENDED
BY THE DILIGENT
EFFORTS OF INVESTIGATORS.
- MR. MAYOR,
IS HE BEING CHARGED WITH
ALL OF THE MURDERS,
OR JUST TWO...
- UM, IT IS MY
UNDERSTANDING THAT, UH...
- UH, WE ARE CHARGING
THE LAST TWO INCIDENTS,
BUT IT IS MY
UNDERSTANDING THAT
HE IS SUSPECTED IN
ALL OF THE CRIMES.
AND WE'RE WAITING FOR
DNA TEST RESULTS.
INDICATIONS ARE THAT HE
MAY BE MENTALLY INCAPACITATED
AND THEREFORE
ADDITIONAL PROSECUTIONS WOULD
PROVE REDUNDANT.
- I'D ALSO LIKE TO CREDIT
DEPUTY COMMISSIONER FOR
OPERATIONS DANIELS
WITH NOT ONLY BRINGING THESE
CASES TO THEIR
PROPER CONCLUSION,
BUT BUT ALSO FOR SOLVING
LAST YEAR'S SLAYINGS
IN THE VACANT ROWHOUSES.
HE HAS GIVEN US SUCH
EXCELLENT WORK THAT
I THINK THAT NOW IS AS GOOD
A TIME AS ANY TO ANNOUNCE
THAT WE WILL BE SENDING
THE DEPUTY'S NAME FORWARD
TO THE CITY COUNCIL
FOR CONFIRMATION AS
BALTIMORE POLICE COMMISSIONER.
ACTING COMMISSIONER RAWLS,
TO WHOM I AM ALSO
EXTREMELY GRATEFUL,
WILL SERVE IN AN
ADVISORY CAPACITY PENDING
NEW RESPONSIBILITIES
AT CITY HALL.
- SCOTT, YOU SHOULD BE
WORKING THE MAIN BAR
ON THE ARREST WITH ALMA.
- I AM...
- WE'RE GOING TO WANT
YOUR BYLINE IN THIS COVERAGE.
- YEAH, I DON'T FEEL
SO WELL
MY STOMACH...
I THINK I GOTTA GO HOME.
SORRY.
- HAVING DUCKED THE BULLET
ON THAT HOMELESS MESS,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
THE MAYOR AND I BOTH
APPRECIATE YOUR DISCRETION.
BUT RIGHT NOW WE CAN'T
TAKE OUR EYES OFF
THE BALL WHEN IT COMES
TO CRIME OVERALL...
LOOKING AT YOUR WEEKLY
U.C.R.s FROM THE DISTRICTS,
I AM NOT SEEING THE KIND
OF DECLINE THAT'S GOING
TO MEASURE OUT TO A TEN
PERCENT DROP IN THE QUARTER.
- THEY'RE CLEAN.
- EXCUSE ME.
- THE STATS ARE CLEAN.
THEY'RE GONNA STAY CLEAN.
EITHER WE FIX THIS
POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND THE CRIME GOES DOWN,
OR WE DON'T
AND THE CRIME STAYS UP.
- COMMISSIONER, WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT A LITTLE HELP
IN THE NEXT COUPLE QUARTERS.
THAT'S ALL...
- NO. I CAN'T.
- YOU'RE QUIET ON
THE HOMELESS FIASCO,
BUT THIS MAKES
YOU SQUEAL?
WHAT THE--
- TELL THE MAYOR HIS
STATS WILL BE CLEAN.
BEFORE THE ELECTION,
AFTER THE ELECTION...
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
THEY CAN'T FIRE YOU.
NOT WITHOUT IT BOUNCING
BACK ON CITY HALL.
IF YOU DON'T MIND BEING
BURIED IN SOME BACKROOM UNIT,
YOU CAN STAY FOR AS
LONG AS YOU CAN STAND IT.
OR UNTIL YOU GET THE PENSION.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
I CAN'T LET YOU DO POLICE WORK.
NOT ANYTHING THAT'S
GOING TO FIND ITS WAY
INTO A COURTROOM.
I WON'T DO THAT.
FOR BOTH OF YOU,
THAT'S OVER.
- SO MARLO WALKS.
- OR YOU GO TO JAIL.
- AND YOU COULDN'T DO
ANY BETTER WITH LEVY, HUH?
I MEAN, GIVING UP
THE MONEY...
- I GOT WHAT I COULD.
YOU LOST THE MONEY TRAIL,
LESTER,
WHEN YOU DECIDED TO START
COLORING OUTSIDE OF THE LINES.
THIS ISN'T ON ME.
- WHAT THE FUCK YOU MEAN
YOU SELLING?
- I'M SELLIN' THE CONNECT.
- HOW MUCH, YO?
- TEN MILLION.
- GODDAMN.
- OR A HIGH BIDDER IF
I HEAR TEN FROM MORE
THAN ONE OF Y'ALL.
IF YOU ALL THINK IT
AIN'T WORTH THAT,
I STICK THAT SHIT BACK
IN MY POCKET AND Y'ALL
CAN GO BACK TO RUNNIN'
THAT STEPPED-ON NEW YORK SHIT.
- YOU DON'T MIND ME ASKIN',
WHY YOU SELLIN'?
I MEAN, EVEN FROM INSIDE
HERE, YOU CAN TAKE A SLICE
FOR JUST LAYIN'
IN THE CUT, NIGGA.
- I AIN'T GONNA BE
IN HERE LONG.
CASE THEY GOT AGAINST ME
ALREADY FALLIN' APART.
BUT THE TRUTH IS,
I'M DONE WITH THIS
GANGSTA SHIT.
I'VE BEEN THERE,
DONE THAT.
- YOU SOMETHIN' ELSE
OTHER THAN A GANGSTA?
- BUSINESSMAN.
YEAH, TALL MAN,
I CAN'T GET THAT SHIT WRAPPED
AROUND MY HEAD NEITHER.
ANYWAY, Y'ALL CAN'T GET
MY PRICE UP,
MAYBE Y'ALL POOL YOUR MONEY.
BUT SUPPLY ONLY GONNA DEAL
WITH Y'ALL AFTER
I MAKE THE INTRO.
THEN I'M OUT.
- YOU'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
I THOUGHT DANIELS WAS
YOUR BOY.
- WE'VE BOTH GOT A PROBLEM
IF CRIME DOESN'T DROP.
CARCETTI LOSES THE
STATEHOUSE AND YOU AREN'T MAYOR.
AND EVEN IF HE WINS,
NERESE, YOU'RE STUCK WITH
A POLICE COMMISSIONER
THAT WON'T WORK WITH YOU.
- OH, I'M NOT STUCK
WITH ANYTHING.
DANIELS EITHER COMES
AROUND OR HE'S DONE.
- WE JUST ANOINTED HIM.
WE CAN'T GO BACK
ON THAT NOW. HE KNOWS IT.
- EITHER HE LEARNS HIS PLACE
OR HE'LL BE OFFERING TO RESIGN.
OH, YOU AIN'T THE ONLY ONE
KNOWS HOW TO PLAY THIS GAME.
- WHAT TO SAY ABOUT
THIS PIECE OF WORK?
FUCK IF I DON'T FIND
MYSELF WITHOUT THE RIGHT WORDS.
ME, AS GIFTED A GOLDEN THROAT
AS ANY OF YOU COCKSUCKERS,
BEING LOOSED FROM RELIGION,
ARE EVER LIKELY TO HEAR.
WHAT CAN I SAY ABOUT
THE DEARLY DEPARTED?
I MEAN, REALLY...
- HE DIED YOUNG. TOO YOUNG.
- NOT EVEN FORTY YEARS OLD.
- THOUGH HAD IT LIVED,
HIS DICK WOULDA BEEN
A HUNDRED AND THIRTY-FOUR...
- SHUT UP.
IT'S COMING TO ME...
HE WAS THE BLACK SHEEP,
THE PERMANENT PARIAH.
HE ASKED NO QUARTER OF
THE BOSSES AND NONE WAS GIVEN.
HE LEARNED NO LESSONS,
HE ACKNOWLEDGED NO MISTAKES,
HE WAS AS STUBBORN A MIC
AS EVER STUMBLED OUT OF
THE NORTHEAST PARISHES TO
TAKE A PATROLMAN'S SHIELD.
HE BROOKED NO AUTHORITY.
HE DID WHAT HE
WANTED TO DO
AND HE SAID WHAT HE
WANTED TO SAY
AND IN THE END,
HE GAVE YOU THE CLEARANCES.
HE'S NATURAL POLICE.
YES, HE WAS.
AND I DON'T SAY THAT
ABOUT MANY PEOPLE.
EVEN WHEN THEY'RE HERE
ON THE FELT,
I DON'T GIVE THAT ONE UP
UNLESS IT HAPPENS TO BE TRUE.
NATURAL POH-LEECE.
BUT CHRIST,
WHAT AN ASSHOLE.
AND I'M TALKIN' ABOUT
THE ORDINARY,
GAPING ORIFICE THAT
ALL OF US POSSESS.
I MEAN AN ALL-ENCOMPASSING,
ALL-CONSUMING,
OUT OF PROPORTION TO EVERY
OTHER FACET OF HIS
HUMANITY CHASM.
FROM WHOSE BORNE,
IF I MAY QUOTE SHAKESPEARE,
NO TRAVELER HAS EVER RETURNED.
- THE FUCK DID I DO?
- SHUT THE FUCK UP.
YOU'RE DEAD TO US NOW.
- HEY, HEY...
- HO, HERE'S HIS
PARTNER IN CRIME.
- NOW, NOW. BE GENTLE.
BE GENTLE.
I'M A CIVILIAN NOW.
- YOUR PAPERS WENT IN,
HUH?
- YEAH, THIS AFTERNOON.
THIRTY-TWO YEARS..
- AND FOUR MONTHS.
- MMM MMM.
Y'ALL DID A
FINE JOB WITH HIM, YOU DID.
HE LOOK TO BE ABOUT TEN
YEARS YOUNGER THAN I REMEMBER.
- C'MON, THERE'S ENOUGH ROOM
FOR BOTH OF YOU TO BE LAID OUT.
- ONE AT A TIME.
YOU DON'T CROWD A MAN
AT HIS OWN WAKE.
- COME ON, LESTER?
COME AND SNUGGLE.
- KEEP OUR SECRETS, JIMMY.
I GOT SHARDENE WITH ME TONIGHT.
- IF YOU GENTLEMEN
WILL SPARE US
THIS UNFORTUNATE
HOMOEROTIC LAPSE,
I WILL CONCLUDE MY
ELEGIAC REMARKS...
- THEN DO IT,
YOU GABBY MOTHERFUCKER...
- TO CONCLUDE...
TO CONCLUDE, I SAY...
HE GAVE US THIRTEEN
YEARS ON THE LINE...
NOT ENOUGH FOR A PENSION...
BUT ENOUGH FOR US TO
KNOW THAT HE WAS..
- PUT THE FUCKING
SONG ON, HUE...
- DESPITE HIS NEGLIGIBLE
IRISH ANCESTRY...
HIS DEFECTS OF
PERSONALITY...
AND HIS INCONSTANT
SOBRIETY AND HYGIENE...
A TRUE MURDER POLICE.
JIMMY...
I SAY THIS SERIOUSLY.
IF I WAS LAYING THERE DEAD
ON SOME BALTIMORE STREET CORNER,
I'D WANT IT TO BE YOU
STANDING OVER ME,
CATCHING THE CASE.
- BULLSHIT.
- BECAUSE, BROTHER,
WHEN YOU WERE GOOD,
YOU WERE THE BEST WE HAD.
- SHIT, IF YOU WAS LAYIN'
THERE DEAD ON SOME CORNER,
IT WAS PROBABLY JIMMY
THAT DONE YA.
- FUCK YOU!
IF YOU CAUGHT THE CASE,
YOU'D BE STANDING THERE
PISSIN' IN MY EAR.
- HOW DID NERESE CAMPBELL
GET IT?
- YOU THINK I ASKED?
DO YOU THINK IT EVEN MATTERS?
SHE GAVE IT TO ME BECAUSE
SHE THOUGHT YOU'D LISTEN TO ME.
- SO NOW THEY WANT
ME TO GO.
- THE WAY SHE EXPRESSED IT
IS THAT SHE WANTED YOU
TO STAY IF YOU COULD COME
TO YOUR SENSES.
- COME TO MY SENSES.
SHE WANTS ME TO JUKE
THE STATS FOR CARCETTI.
THIS QUARTER AND THE NEXT...
HIDE THE CRIME,
GET HIM ELECTED AS GOVERNOR
AND MAKE HER THE MAYOR.
- SO DO IT.
BURRELL JUKED
THEM BEFORE YOU.
WARREN FRASIER
BEFORE HIM.
AND AFTER YOU'RE GONE,
RAWLS OR WHOEVER
WILL JUKE THEM. SO WHAT?
- I'LL SWALLOW A LIE
WHEN I HAVE TO.
I'VE SWALLOWED A FEW
BIG ONES LATELY.
BUT THE STAT GAMES...
THAT LIE, IT'S WHAT RUINED
THIS DEPARTMENT.
SHINING UP SHIT AND
CALLING IT GOLD,
SO MAJORS BECOME COLONELS
AND MAYORS BECOME GOVERNORS.
PRETENDING TO DO POLICE WORK
WHILE ONE GENERATION FUCKING
TRAINS THE NEXT HOW NOT
TO DO THE JOB.
AND THAT...
I LOOKED CARCETTI
IN THE EYE.
I SHOOK HIS HAND.
I ASKED HIM IF
HE WAS FOR REAL.
THIS IS THE LIE
I CAN'T LIVE WITH.
IF I DO, THEN NERESE HAS ME
IN HER POCKET WHENEVER
SHE WANTS ME.
AND I'M NO GOOD TO
ANYONE LIKE THAT.
- THEN GO.
WITHDRAW FOR PERSONAL REASONS,
OR HEALTH REASONS.
WHATEVER.
YOU'VE GOT YOUR LAW DEGREE.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO STARVE.
BUT IF YOU DON'T GO,
THEY'LL WRECK BOTH OF US.
- THERE'S NOT ENOUGH
IN HERE TO INDICT ME.
AND THE JOKE OF IT IS,
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH
THE LAST FEW DAYS TO HAVE
THEM INDICTED.
- FOR WHAT?
THEN USE IT, CEDRIC.
OR AT LEAST THREATEN TO.
- PEOPLE WILL GET HURT.
PEOPLE I CARE ABOUT.
- THEN YOU'RE DONE.
THERE'S ENOUGH IN THAT FILE
THAT YOU'LL NEVER MAKE
IT THROUGH
CONFIRMATION HEARINGS.
AND ENOUGH SO THAT MY
CAREER IS DEAD BEFORE IT
EVEN GETS STARTED.
THE TREE THAT DOESN'T BEND,
BREAKS, CEDRIC.
- BEND TOO FAR,
YOU'RE ALREADY BROKEN.
- MARLO ON A WALK.
AND THE MONEY, JIMMY.
SHE GAVE THAT AWAY, TOO.
- YEAH.
- WE DON'T GET TO
FOLLOW THE MONEY.
HEY...
WONDERIN' WHERE YOU WAS...
- DIDN'T KNOW IF I SHOULD
COME OUT ON THIS HERE...
- WHY THE FUCK NOT?
- WAS ME WHO TOLD DANIELS.
I DIDN'T WANT TO DO
IT BEHIND YOUR BACK,
BUT IT HAD TO BE DONE.
ANYWAY, IT WAS GREAT BEIN'
ON THE JOB WITH Y'ALL.
I JUST WANTED TO SAY
THAT TOO, I GUESS.
- SO WHAT?
YOU AIN'T GONNA DRINK
WITH ME?
- I AM IF YOU WANT...
- DETECTIVE, IF YOU THINK
IT NEEDED DOIN',
I GUESS IT DID.
- YOU COMIN'?
- MILTON CAME
WITH SIX HUNDRED.
AN' LITTLE GLEN IS
IN FOR THREE.
- I GOT FIVE FROM ME
AN' I GOT FIVE FROM
CHINAMAN TO COVER.
- I CAN GO THAT.
NO THING.
- WHAT?
MOTHERFUCKER, WHERE YOU GET
THAT KIND OF SCRATCH?
- YOU DON'T THINK CHEESE
KNOW THIS HERE GAME?
WE SELLIN' DOPE AN' COKE
IN BALTIMORE, NIGGA,
ANY OF Y'ALL AIN'T GOT
THAT KIND OF MONEY
NEED BE ASHAMED.
- YOU STILL PUTTIN' UP MORE
THAN YOUR SHARE WITH THAT.
- THE WAY I LOOK AT IT,
WE ALL GONNA BE MORE
THAN PAID ONCE WE OWN
THE CONNECT, SO...
- SHIT, NIGGA,
WE WAS GOOD WHEN
YOUR UNCLE HAD IT.
YOU HAD TO GO AHEAD AND
PUT UP WITH MARLO...
- SEE THAT.
SEE NOW, THAT'S JUST THE
WRONG WAY TO LOOK AT IT.
'CAUSE JOE HAD HIS TIME
AND OMAR PUT AN END TO THAT,
THEN MARLO HAD HIS TIME,
SHORT AS IT WAS,
AN' THE POLICE PUT
AN END TO THAT.
AND NOW, MOTHERFUCKER,
IT'S OUR TIME.
MINES AND YOURS.
BUT INSTEAD OF JUST
SHUTTIN' UP AND KICKIN' IN,
YOU GONNA STAND THERE CRYIN'
THAT BACK-IN-THE-DAY SHIT.
- CHEESE...
- THERE AIN'T NO BACK
IN THE DAY, NIGGA.
AIN'T NO NOSTALGIA
TO THIS SHIT HERE.
THERE'S JUST THE STREET
AND THE GAME
AND WHAT HAPPEN HERE TODAY.
- YOU RIGHT.
- WHEN IT WAS MY UNCLE,
I WAS WITH MY UNCLE.
WHEN IT WAS MARLO,
I WAS WITH HIM.
BUT NOW, NIGGA--
- WHAT THE FUCK
DID YOU DO THAT FOR?
NOW WE SHORT THE NINE.
- THAT WAS FOR JOE.
- THIS SENTIMENTAL
MOTHERFUCKER JUST COST US MONEY.
- HEY, ALMA...
I JUST HEARD.
- THE CARROLL
COUNTY BUREAU?
THAT'S HOW THEY
PUNISH ME?
WHY NOT JUST SEND MY ASS
ALL THE WAY TO PENNSYLVANIA?
- WHAT'D THEY TELL YOU?
- THAT I DID AN EXCELLENT JOB.
THAT THIS HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH ANYTHING BUT TRYING
TO MAKE THE COUNTY
BUREAUS STRONGER.
- ALMA, I DIDN'T TELL
THEM ABOUT THE NOTEPAD.
I LEFT THAT PART OUT.
- I TOLD THEM.
WHEN I HEARD YOU WERE
IN TROUBLE,
I WENT TO WHITING,
TOLD HIM I THOUGHT YOU
WERE RIGHT ABOUT SCOTT.
I TOLD HIM ABOUT THE NOTEPAD.
DID HE MAKE ALL OF IT UP?
THE CALLS FROM THE KILLER?
THE PICTURES?
- SOME, NOT ALL.
- WHY?
- LOOK AROUND.
THE POND IS SHRINKING.
THE FISH ARE NERVOUS.
GET SOME PROFILE,
WIN A PRIZE...
MAYBE FIND A BIGGER
POND SOMEWHERE.
WHITING, KLEBANOW, TEMPLETON...
THEY SNATCH A PULITZER OR TWO,
AND THEY ARE UP
AND GONE FROM THIS PLACE.
FOR THEM, THAT'S WHAT
THIS IS ALL ABOUT.
ME?
I'M TOO FUCKIN'
SIMPLE-MINDED FOR THAT.
I JUST WANTED TO SEE
SOMETHING NEW EVERY DAY...
AND WRITE A
STORY WITH IT.
ALMA, YOU'LL WRITE
YOUR WAY OUTTA CARROLL
IN NO TIME, WATCH.
- ABOUT AS FAST
AS YOU EDIT
YOUR WAY OFF THE COPY
DESK, HUH?
- CONGRATULATIONS,
SERGEANT GOETTE.
I KNOW YOU'LL DO WELL
IN THE EASTERN.
GLAD I GOT TO DO
THIS AT LEAST.
CONGRATULATIONS,
LIEUTENANT CARVER.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
I'M JUST SORRY IT WON'T
BE YOU I'M SERVING UNDER.
- WORD GETS AROUND, HUH?
- IT'S ON W.B.A.L. TODAY.
THEY SAID YOU'RE LEAVING
FOR FAMILY REASONS...
- I GUESS I GOT SOME KIDS
SOMEWHERE I DON'T
EVEN KNOW ABOUT.
THEY SAY ON B.A.L.
WHO THEY'RE SENDING UP
AS ACTING COMMISSIONER?
- SAY IT AIN'T SO.
- LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
AS WHAT MAY BE MY
LAST OFFICIAL ACT
AS A BALTIMORE
POLICE OFFICER,
ALLOW ME TO CONGRATULATE ALL
OF THE PROMOTED OFFICERS,
THEIR FAMILIES,
THEIR FELLOW OFFICERS,
AND THEIR FRIENDS.
- YOU AIN'T CAREFUL,
THEY MAY MAKE YOU MAJOR.
THEN YOU'LL BE TRULY FUCKED.
GOOD JOB.
- THANKS.
- I'M PROUD OF YOU.
- SEE NOW,
THERE YOU GO
GIVIN' A FUCK WHEN IT
AIN'T YOUR TURN
TO GIVE A FUCK.
LEHMAN'S SQUAD WAS UP.
- I NEEDED THE O.T.
- YEAH, AN' NOW
YOU GOT A SHOOTING WITH NO WITS,
NO SUSPECT AND NO PRAYER
OF IT GOIN' TO BLACK.
PICKIN' UP THE PHONE LIKE
A GODDAMN ROOKIE.
SHAME ON YOU.
- STOP SQUEALIN' LIKE A BITCH.
AN' MAKE SURE YOU DON'T STEP
ON THAT SHELL CASING BEHIND YOU.
- I AIN'T GONNA KICK NO
SHELL CASINGS BEHIND ME.
IT'S RIGHT THERE ON THE SIDE.
I'M GONNA STEP BACK AND KICK
NO DAMN SHELL CASING
YOU DON'T MARK WITH LETTERS
AND NUMBERS.
- I UNDERSTAND.
AND YOU GOTTA BE IN THE SYSTEM.
THEY SENT YOU THE FORM.
- THEY TOLD ME THAT
WASN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
THEY SAID THEY WANTED
THE OTHER PAPER WORK.
- AND YOU SAID YOU APPLIED
FOR S.S.I., MR. BELTON?
- YES, MA'AM.
- WELL, LET'S GO
INSIDE AND LOOK IT UP ON
THE COMPUTER.
- HEY, YOU REMEMBER ME?
I BROUGHT THIS GUY IN
A FEW WEEKS BACK,
I JUST WANTED TO SEE
HOW HE WAS...
- HE WANDERED OUT AFTER
A COUPLE NIGHTS.
SORRY.
- WHERE...
WHERE DO THE HOMELESS
GO AROUND HERE?
- DIFFERENT PLACES.
DOWN BY THE RIVER,
OVER IN THE
WAREHOUSE DISTRICT...
SOME OF THE PLACES,
I DON'T REALLY THINK
IT WOULD BE SAFE
FOR YOU TO GO...
- I'M POLICE.
WELL, I USED TO BE.
- WAIT HERE.
I'LL SEE IF I
CAN FIND YOU A MAP.
- THANKS.
- COME ON, MR. BELTON.
- AND IF THE MAJOR COULD FIND
HIS ASS WITH HIS HAND,
HE'D KNOW THAT THIS WE HAVE
MORE THAN ENOUGH FOR US
TO BE UP ON A PEN REGISTER.
LIEUTENANT CARVER TOLD HIM SO,
BUT FUCK IF HE ISN'T TRYING
TO SHUT THIS THING DOWN.
ALL'S I'M SAYIN' IS A
PHONE CALL OR TWO AND
YOU'RE GONNA FIND OUT
THAT THEY'RE GETTIN'
SOME KINDA PRESSURE FROM
SOMEWHERE TO SIT ON THIS THING,
EVEN THOUGH WE'VE TIED
THREE KILLINGS TO THIS CREW.
- DOES THE POLICE
COMMISSIONER KNOW?
- HIM?
HE WOULDN'T KNOW POLICE
WORK IF IT TOOK DOWN HIS
FRONT DOOR ON A WARRANT.
JUST...
KEEP MY NAME OUT OF IT.
- NEW WESTPORT IS LIKE
HOWARD STREET TEN YEARS AGO,
EXCEPT THE LAND'S CHEAPER
AND THERE'S MORE POTENTIAL
FOR MIXED-USE BECAUSE OF
THE WATERFRONT LOCATION.
- THERE YOU ARE.
- YOU CAN'T PUT A PRICE
ON A WATERVIEW.
- OH, YES, YOU CAN.
YOU DEFINITELY CAN.
- ANDY, HE'S GOTTA MEET
TOMMY AND THEY'RE LEAVING EARLY,
SO LET ME BORROW HIM
FOR A MOMENT.
- SURE, NO PROBLEM.
NICE TO MEET YOU,
MR. STANFIELD.
- YOU KNOW WHO YOU
WERE TALKING TO?
- NAH.
- ANDY KRAWCZYK.
VERY CONNECTED.
VERY BIG WITH DEVELOPMENT
AROUND THE HARBOR.
HE'S SOMEONE YOU'RE
GONNA WANNA KNOW WELL,
BUT KID, DO NOT...
DO NOT GET IN A ROOM
WITH HIM ALONE.
YOU WANT ME IN THERE WITH YOU,
BELIEVE ME.
OTHERWISE, GUYS LIKE THAT
WILL BLEED YOU...
I WANT YOU TO MEET TOMMY
FLANAGAN BEFORE HE LEAVES...
- YEAH, GIMME A MINUTE.
I NEED TO, UM...
- BATHROOM?
- YEAH.
- DOWN THE HALL TO THE RIGHT.
HEY, WATCH THAT STUFF.
YOU'LL PUT ON WEIGHT.
- BUT NEXT TIME,
I WANT YOU TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU WATCH THIS MONEY...
- UH-UH. DON'T...
UMM-UH. DON'T DO IT.
TIME TO GIVE THAT UP.
- DO YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
- NAME'S VINSON.
USED TO BE MARLO'S BANK,
BUT MARLO AIN'T 'ROUND NO MORE,
AND YOU STILL MOVIN' MONEY
FOR OTHER PLAYERS SO...
I'M THINKIN' SOME OF THAT
MONEY NEED TO BE MINE.
- SHIT...
YOU JUST A BOY.
THAT'S JUST YOUR KNEE.
- THAT MOTHERFUCKER SHOT ME.
- NICE DOIN' BUSINESS,
GENTLEMEN.
- NO WAY, THAT'S BULLSHIT.
I HEARD IT DIFFERENT.
THE REAL STORY ABOUT OMAR
IS THAT A BUNCH OF COPS
MADE IT LOOK LIKE THEM
NEW YORK BOYS KILLED HIM.
BUT IT WAS THEM.
THEY'RE THE ONES THAT
REALLY KILLED HIM.
- LISTEN, MOTHERFUCKER,
I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
THEM POLICE HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
NO NEW YORK BOYS NEITHER.
SO OMAR'S GOT AN A.K.,
RIGHT?
BUT HE'S SURROUNDED.
IT'S LIKE EIGHT,
NINE MOTHERFUCKERS UP THERE
AND THEY ALL GOT NINES.
BUT HE LIKE,
"YOU ALL THINK YOU..."
- FUCK YOU LOOKIN' AT?
- YOU, NIGGA.
- YOU KNOW WHO I AM?
- NIGGA, YOU KNOW
WHO I AM?
- OH, SHIT!
- YEAH...
- ON ME, ALL RIGHT?
- THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS A GREAT DAY FOR
DEMOCRATS AND IT'S A
GREAT DAY FOR MARYLAND.
- HEY, ZORZI.
I HOPE I GET THIS BY E-DOT.
- OKAY, THREE MINUTES,
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE.
DON'T GET YOUR
PANTIES IN A KNOT.
- COMMISSIONER VALCHEK.
- MADAM PROSECUTOR,
GENTLEMEN...
FIRST CASE UP AND
I HAVE TO RECUSE MYSELF.
- YOUR HONOR,
I APPRECIATE YOUR CONCERN.
- CONGRATULATIONS,
SUPERINTENDENT.
WELCOME ABOARD.
- THANK YOU, GOVERNOR.
HAPPY TO BE ABOARD.
- THANK YOU.
LARRY...
LET'S GO HOME.